PHONE: (646) 468 63698

EMAIL: jjramirezuribe@gmail.com

WEBSITE: www.whoisjuan.me

# JUAN JOSE RAMIREZ PRODUCT MANAGER & UX SPECIALIST

Innovation-driven technology UX Designer & Product Professional with extensive international experience and education in all facets and elements of product life cycle from research, development, and testing to shipping, launch and growth.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Entertainment Technology Carnegie Mellon University, 2015

Bachelor of Business Administration Colegio de Estudios Superios de Administracion, 2012

Rapid Assesment Program Connect San Diego, 2012

Advanced Certificate Afiiliate Marketing University of San Francisco, 2010

# PRINCIPLES & PRACTICES

Product Strategy and Roadmapping, Fast Prototyping, Wireframing, User Experience Design, Usability Research, User Testing, Multi-Variate Testing, Web/App Metrics Analysis, Human-Computer Interaction, Object-Oriented Programming, Functional Programming, Market Research, Customer Focus Research, User Acquisition, Growth Analysis, Business Model Generation and Analysis, Startup Financials.

## **TECHNOLOGY**

HTML & CSS, Python, Javascript (jQuery, Node.js), SQL, Sketch, Adobe Photoshop, Axure, Invision, Mixpanel.

#### **AWARDS**

2014 Indiecade Official Selection Finalist - The Last Egg

2011 Andi Entrepreneurship Award - Usuallee App

## LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native) English (Fluent)

# SELECTED CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

Bogglo, Inc. | New York, NY

Lead Product Manager, Jun 2015-Present

Lead all the product initiatives and product development in Bogglo, a platform (iOS, Android) that allows NYC millennials to buy and sell in seconds. Bogglo brokers the transaction to guarantee that the buyer gets the actual product and the seller gets paid in full. • Manage the development and releases for iOS and Android apps. • Created and executed product strategies to support the growth of the user base resulting in a constant increase of over 150% in the main product KPIs.

• Developed a product framework that increased speed and fluidness of the roadmap and feedback-iteration process, resulting in a solid increase of 110% more solved issues and implemented features.

# Carnegie Mellon University | Pittsburgh, PA

**UX Designer**, 2014 - 2015

Client: Allegheny Health Network.

In joint with AHN, create an app for Allegheny General Hospital to educate people who have been diagnosed with congestive heart failure. The app teaches them about their condition, the implications of their condition and the treatment which consists of medication, diet and activity.

- Create main UX experience and UX flow of the iPad app Create prototypes and conduct user testing with patients Create design documentation to make informed iterations
- Design different interactions to optimize content and narrative.

Client: Chevron and Elizabeth Forward School District.

In joint with EFSD and Chevron, conceptualized and developed an interactive renewable energy lab, with a final deliverable that consisted of an interactive touch dome and educational iPad app.

- Created age-appropriate ux experience through content and narrative development
  - Created and shipped a 48 inch touch screen interactive dome, a game for the dome, and a companion educational app.

Contactive | New York, NY **Product Manager**, 2014

Contactive is a startup (acquired by ThinkingPhones), that is working in a sales productivity platform to enhance customer interactions. Contactive also operates CallelD. The leading Android caller identification solution with more than 1 million downloads.

- Developed API product Created a pricing model for the product Grew the develope API user base from 5 to 200+ through the implementation of a successful growth plan and promotion strategy
- Worked directly with 2 UI designers and 2 engineers.

Usualle | Bogota, COL

# Co-Founder & Head of Product, 2011-2013

Usuallee is a startup that created a visual feedback platform that mashed-up the traditional Q&A format with video. It raised \$200k in seed capital and later spinned off into Mobijob, a profitable micro-job marketplace for the latin market.

- Developed the concept, user experience, specifications (e.g. Wireframes, mockups) and business logic of the Usuallee prototype, an app which creatively connects community and encourages shared problem resolution through visual feedback Conducted 6 months of UX/UI research to inform iterations.
- Designed a financial strategy to raise \$20k using convertible notes Supported operational strategy and requirements to raise \$200k in seed money and created a strategy to acquire the first 100 beta testers.

# Casa Editorial El Tiempo | Bogota, COL

Product Manager, 2011-2012

Casa Editorial El Tiempo is a media conglomerate that operates EL TIEMPO and ELTIEMPO.COM, the most widely read newspaper and most visited news website in Colombia.

- Executed all product-related tasks (e.g. Pipeline, Product Requirements) for ELTIEMPO.COM
- Conducted UX/UI research (e.g. Heuristics evaluation, contextual inquiry) for web/mobile features.
- Managed the blogs' sub-product serving 300+ bloggers and launched several features for that community.

Freelance | Remote

#### Frontend Developer and Digital Strategist, 2010-2011

Developed streamlined, innovative business solutions for nationwide clients and NGOs including dropshipping, small e-commerce, and the creation of affiliate marketing campaigns for various price points through optimization of PPV networks, Facebook Ads, Google Adwords, and Media buying and creation of tailor made websites to serve and convert paid traffic.